2구역 A
현재 위치는?
Two Sector Adam,
what's your location?
지휘부 여기는 12A팀
One Two Adam to Central.
용의자들이 122가 x 레녹스 가에서
남쪽 121가 방향으로 도주 중
Suspects are southbound
on Lenox
at 122 street,
going toward 121.
_
알겠다. 12A팀
10-4, One Two Adam.
야, 야, 야, 야,
저 자식들 왼쪽으로 꺾는다!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
they're cutting left!
지휘부, 여기는 12A
Central, this is One Two Adam.
현재 121가 방향 서쪽으로 향하고 있다.
Now heading westbound on 121.
용의자들은 20대 초반
흑인 남성 두 명이며
Suspects are two black males,
early 20s,
한 명은 후드 티와
검은색 자켓을 입었고,
one in a black jacket
with a hoodie,
다른 한 명은 회색 후드 티에
빨간 자켓을 입었다.
one in a red jacket,
gray hoodie.
둘 다 청바지 차림이다.
Both in blue jeans.
알겠다 12A.
Copy that, One Two Adam.
121가 x 레녹스 가 근방의
대원들은 즉시 지원 투입하도록
I need any available units
to report to 121 and Lenox.
현재 강도 용의자를
추격 중에 있다.
Officers in pursuit
of robbery suspects.
지휘부, 용의자들은 현재
스포츠 용품 가게 옆의 골목
북쪽 방향으로 도주 중에 있다
Central, suspects are now
northbound in an alley
next to the sporting goods store
_
122가로 향할 것으로 보이며
직접 추격하겠다
heading toward 122.
In pursuit.
_
경찰이다!
Hey, police!
A팀 198번 경관
지휘부에 지원을 요청한다!
Sector Adam Shield
198 to Central.
198, 추격할 것.
198, go.
용의자가 바로 앞에서 도주 중이며
현재 직접 도보로 추격 중이다
We're 84,
pursuing suspect on foot
골목에서 122가 방향
북쪽으로 향하고 있다
northbound in an alley
towards 122.
알겠다 198번 경관.
전 대원들은 들어라
Copy that, 198.
Units responding.
A팀이 골목에서 용의자를
도보로 추격 중이다
Be advised, Sector Adam
are on foot in the alley
122가 뱡향 북쪽으로 향하고 있다.
heading northbound toward 122.
A팀 841번이다 지휘부 응답하라!
Sector Adam 841 to Central!
용의자가 철조망 담장을
넘어 도주 중이다!
Suspect scaled
a barbed wire fence!
(잡음) ...
레녹스 가 방향 동쪽으로 도주 중이다!
heading eastbound toward Lenox!
841, 보고받지 못하였다. 다시 보고하라.
841, repeat. I didn't copy that.
841, 다시 보고하라.
841, go again.
_
198, 대기하라.
198, stand by.
841, 보고하라.
841, go.
841, 용의자가 보이는가?
841, do you have a visual?
아니다, 다시 되돌아가고 있는 중이다.
Uh, negative. I'm doubling back.
- 용의자가 격발하였다!
- 모든 대원 대기하라.
- Shots fired!
- All units, stand by.
198, 지휘대형에서 이탈하지 말 것
198, you're breaking up.
지휘부의 지시에 응하라.
Come in to Central.
내 파트너의 위치가 확인되었는가?
Do you have
a 10-7 on my partner?
모든 대원 대기하라.
All units, stand by.
198, 현재 위치는?
198, what is your location?
용의자는 현재...
Suspect is headed...
경찰이다! 손 들어!
Police! Show me your hands!
_
198번, 응답하라.
198, come in to Central.
198번, 들리는가?
198, do you copy?
피해자는 무고하다!
There was no gun!
(피해자는 총을 소지하지 않고 있었다)
There was no gun! There was no gun!
There was no gun!
테드, 제가 듣기로
Ted, I'm learning
이번 총격 사건의 피해자
티모시 브라운은 이른바
that the victim of the shooting,
Timothy Brown, was allegedly
보석상 강도사건에 개입되었다고
전해지고 있습니다.
involved in a jewelry
store robbery
사건 공범은 현재
체포되지 않은 상태입니다.
with an accomplice who
has not been apprehended
그러나 익명을 요구한 고위 경찰
관료의 증언에 따르면
An anonymous high-ranking
official has revealed,
피해자 티모시 브라운은
평범한 대학생이었으며
however, that Timothy Brown,
경찰에 총을 맞을 당시 총을
소지하지 않은 상태였다고 합니다.
a college student, was unarmed
at the time of the shooting.
시청자 여러분들도 아시다시피
불과 지난 1주일 동안
This is the second fatality
at the hands of police
경찰의 의해 민간인이 2명이나
희생당하였습니다
in less than a week,
and as you know,
지난 번의 피해자 또한
여기에서 멀지 않은 곳에서
the other victim was gunned
down just blocks from here
비무장 상태에서 경찰에
총을 맞았습니다.
and was unarmed as well.
무장을 하지 않은 민간인을 말입니다!
There was no gun!
몇 번을 말씀드려요
I don't know how many
times I got to say it.
그 놈이 총을 갖고 있었어요
저한테도 한 방 쐈다고요.
He had a gun;
the kid took a shot at me.
그 점에 대해 보고했었는가?
You called it in?
네, 물론 보고했죠
Yeah, I called it in.
그럼 총은 어떻게 돼먹은거야?
So what happened to the gun?
몰라요
I don't know.
제가 그걸 알면서 숨기겠어요?
Don't you think I would
tell you that if I knew?
저 밖에 200명이 넘는 군중들이
야구방망이로 제 머리를 뽀개려고
드는 판에 제가 왜 거짓말을 하겠어요
There's 200 people outside
that would like to take
a baseball bat to my head!
_
보석상을 턴 건 그 녀석인데
A kid robs a jewelry store,
제가 왜 의심을 받고 있어야 하는거죠?
and it's my word
that's in question?
케빈, 진정해
Kevin, relax, buddy.
자네를 못 믿는게 아니네
No one's questioning
your word, Kevin.
우린 사건의 전모를 알아야 할 뿐이야
We're just trying to
work out what happened.
우리도 정보를 더 많이 알아야
The more we know,
the more we can control
저 바깥에 무리들에게
해명을 하고 사태가 진정되지 않겠는가
any misinformation that
gets out there, all right?
그 놈들이 골목에서 찢어지자
트레이 경관이랑 저는 흩어져서
추격을 하기로 했어요
Trey and I got separated
when the two of them
split up in the alley.
_
용의자는 현재 122가로 향하는
터널에서 북쪽 방향으로 도주 중이다
Suspect is running northbound
in a tunnel towards 122.
멈춰! 멈춰라!
Stop, stop!
경찰이다!
Police!
멈춰! 멈춰라!
Stop! Stop!
여기는 198번
현재 골목 아래로 용의자를 추격 중이다
198 in pursuit
down the alley behind, uh...
198번 대기하라
198, stand by.
841번, 841번 경관
용의자가 보이는가?
841...841, do you have a visual?
아니다, 다시 되돌아가고 있는 중이다.
Uh, negative. I'm doubling back.
_
지원 요청! 지원 요청! 용의자가 격발하였다
10-13, 10-13, shots fired!
모든 대원 대기하라
All... stand by.
198, 지휘대.. (..공백..) 마라.
198, you're breaking... Central.
경찰이다! 꼼짝마!
Police! Don't move!
손 들어!
Show me your hands!
_
케빈! 괜찮아?
Kevin, you all right?!
응, 저 놈이 나한테 총을 쏘려 했어
Yeah, he took a shot at me.
198, 보고하라.
198, come in to Central.
198, 응답하라!
198, do you copy?
그러니까 용의자는 자네에게 총을 쏘고난 뒤
그 총을 버렸고,
So you're saying that after
he popped off the one shot,
_
자네가 지원을 요청한 거라고?
he ditched the gun
and you called in a 13?
제가 꾸며낸 말이 아니고
진짜로 그랬다고요
That's not what I'm saying;
that's what happened.
좋아
Okay.
지휘부에서는 네 지원 요청을
보고받지 못했다고 해.
Central never heard your 13.
무전기가 제대로 작동하지 않았나보죠
Well, that must be the first time
that the radios didn't work.
그 자가 도망가는 동안
총을 소지하고 있었던가?
Did he have a gun in his
hand while he was running?
아뇨
No.
그리고 그 자가 자켓 안주머니에
손을 넣어 총을 꺼내려 하여
그 자를 쏘았다는건가?
And you saw him reaching into
his pocket when you shot him?
그 자가 돌아서고 있었는데
손이 자켓 안주머니에 있었어요
He spun around, his hand was
up by his inside pocket.
그럼 그 피해자가 총을
어디다 버렸다는건가?
Which alley could he have
dumped the gun in?
몰라요 거기가 엄청 복잡해서요
I don't know.
It was like a maze in there.
제발요 저기.. 형사님들
Look, guys... detectives,
전 굳이 이럴 필요 없거든요?
I don't have to talk to you.
내무조사과에서 진술을 요구받기 전까지
아직 48시간 동안은 사실 자유거든요?
I have 48 hours before
I can be compelled
to give a statement to IAB,
but I know what that looks like.
형사님들 표정 보니
어떻게 생각하시는지 뻔히 보이네요
제가 그 48시간동안
거짓말을 짜낼 거라고 생각하시는거죠?
You both think that gives me
48 hours to perfect my lie.
전 거짓말하는게 아니예요
I am not lying.
그 자식이 저한테 총을 먼저 쐈다고요
That kid took a shot at me.
전 분명 지원을 요청했어요
I called a 13.
_
여기 그대로 있어
Stay there.
움직이지 마 !
Don't move!
_
지원을 요청한다! 여기는 1-2 관할
10-13! One-two precinct.
난동을 부리는 시민들이
경찰서를 무력으로 침입하려 하고 있다!
Disorderly group trying to
forcibly enter the precinct.
_
어딜 만져!
Get off of me!
CSI:NY S09E17
Today is Life
Original Air Date : 2013. 02. 22.
sync and corrections by bellows
www.addic7ed.com
♪ Out here in the fields
♪ I fight for my meals
♪ I get my back into my living
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
sync and corrections by bellows
www.addic7ed.com
한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
재배포 허용. 수정은 제작자와 협의 하에
여기 맨하탄 경찰서 앞에서
진실을 요구하는 시민들의 시위는
What began
as a peaceful demonstration
폭력 사태로 번지게 되었고,
escalated into a
bloody confrontation
this morning inside this
Manhattan precinct.
_
수십명의 경찰관과 시민들이
부상을 입었습니다.
Dozens of police officers
and civilians were injured.
10명 이상의 시민들이 연행되었으며,
At least ten arrests
시위대와 경찰 사이의 긴장은
아직도 완화될 기미가 보이지 않고 있습니다.
were made, and it doesn't
look like the tension
has come even close to subsiding.
_
시위대의 규모는 현재 1,500명으로 늘어났으며
The crowd out here has grown
to approximately 1,500,
시위대가 바라는 진실의 규명은
아직도 미궁에 빠져 있습니다.
and no one is any closer
to getting the answers
that they sought,
_
현재 故 티모시 브라운의 애인인
토리 벨 씨와 함께하고 있는데요
particularly Tori Bell,
Timothy Brown's girlfriend,
who is here with me now.
_
벨 씨, 혹시 하고 싶은 말씀이 있나요?
Miss Bell, is there anything
you'd like to say?
팀은 강도가 아니예요.
Tim didn't rob anybody.
경찰들이 말하길 팀이
보석상에서 강도사건을 벌였다고 하지만
They're saying he
robbed a jewelry store,
정말 말도 안되는 소리예요
and I can't believe
he would do that.
팀은 전혀 폭력적인 사람이 아니예요
He wasn't a violent person, and...
그리고 강도짓 따위를 벌일 리가 없고
그런 걸로 남에게 손을 벌릴 사람이 아니예요
I' never seen him raise
his hand towards anyone,
let alone rob a jewelry store.
_
정말 좋은 사람이예요
He was a good man.
정말 사랑했던 사람이예요
I loved him very much.
그저 진실을 알고 싶을 뿐이예요
I just want to know
what happened.
그 자식이 먼저 총을 쐈어요
The mope took a shot at him.
그게 사건의 전모죠
That's what happened.
홉킨스 경관에게 총을 쏘는 걸 보셨다고요?
You saw him take a shot at Hopkins?
아뇨.
No.
총소리는 들었나요?
You hear the shot?
아뇨.
No.
그러면 용의자 브라운이 홉킨스 경관에게
총을 쐈다는건 어떻게 아는 거죠?
So how do you know that Brown
took a shot at Hopkins?
케빈이 그렇다고 했으면
그런 거예요.
Because Kevin said so, and
that's good enough for me.
나는 납득을 못하겠는걸
Well, that's not good enough for me.
나뿐만아니라 윗 부서 사람들도
납득이 안 될거야
And it's not good enough for
the bosses down at one P.P.
사건의 발단부터 진술해주시죠
Start from the beginning.
내무조사과에 이미 진술했다고요!
Look, I already gave
my statement to IAB.
그럼 우리한테도 말해봐봐.
Well, tell us.
_
상황이 어쩌다 그렇게 꼬였는지
모르겠어요
I can't believe
how out of control this got.
그 양아치 놈들이 보석상 주인 얼굴에
총을 겨누고 보석을 털어가려 했던 게 발단이었죠
All because some punk
wants to buy his jewelry
by sticking a gun
in the owner's face.
_
저 밖에 2천명이나 되는 사람들이
고작 그 도둑놈새끼들 위하자고 저러고 있다니!
2,000 people out
there for this guy.
놈들은 우리가 추격을 시작하자
땅에 보석을 버리기 시작했어요
They were tossing jewelry
on the ground
while we were chasing them.
_
범인들이 도주하는 동안
총을 소지하고 있던걸 보았나요?
Did you see a gun
- in either one's hand while
they were running? - No.
아뇨
- 경찰차를 버리고 추격을 시작하고 난 뒤에는?
- 놈들이 찢어졌어요.
- What happened after you abandoned
your vehicle? - They split up.
저는 골목 왼쪽 방향으로 도망가는
범인을 쫓았죠.
I followed the one kid
down an alleyway to the left.
경찰이다!
Police!
_
멈춰!
Stop!
A팀 841이다, 지휘부 응답하라!
Sector Adam 841 to Central!
용의자가 철조망 담장을
넘어 도주 중이다!
Suspect has scaled
a barbed wire fence!
레녹스 가 방향 동쪽으로
도주하는 것이 마지막으로 목격되었다!
Last seen heading
eastbound toward Lenox!
그러고 난 뒤 저는 길을 돌아서서
홉킨스 경관을 찾으러 갔죠.
That's when I doubled back
to find Hopkins.
그 때 총소리를 들었나요?
Had you heard a shot at that point?
아뇨, 하지만 그렇다고 해서
총을 쏘지 않았다는 건 아니예요
No, but that doesn't mean
that it didn't happen.
골목 환풍기가 비행기 엔진마냥
시끄러워서 소리가 잘 들리지 않았어요
The generator in the alley was
like standing next to an airplane.
- 그럼 총소리를 들은건 언제였죠?
- 코너 하나를 돌고 있던 때였는데..
- So when did you hear the shot?
- I was coming around
one of the corners when...
_
케빈, 괜찮아?
Kevin, you all right?!
응, 저 놈이 나한테 총을 쏘려 했어
Yeah, he took a shot at me.
198, 응답하라.
198, come in to Central.
분명 총을 갖고 있었어
He had a gun.
198, 응답하라.
198, come in to Central.
198, 응답하라!
198, do you copy?
분명 총을 갖고 있었어
He had a gun.
_
♪
어떻게 생각해요?
What do you think?
동료인 홉킨스 경관을 보호하려고
거짓말을 하려는 걸 수도 있지
It would've been so easy for him
to cover for Hopkins and lie.
총소리를 두 번 들었다고 하니까
All he would have to do is
say that he heard two shots,
우리로서는 반박의 여지가 없는거지
and there would be nothing
we could do to dispute it.
그럼 피해자가 정말 홉킨스 경관에게
총을 쐈다고 생각해요?
So you think the vic really did
take a shot at Hopkins?
저 동료 경관은
그렇게 생각하는 것 같아
I think he thinks the vic
took a shot at Hopkins.
그런데,
But the truth is,
당사자인 홉킨스 경관과 티모시 브라운을 빼고는
아무도 그 때의 정확한 진실을 알지 못하지.
no one knows what
happened in that alley
except for Hopkins
and Timothy Brown.
_
증거가 필요해
We need evidence.
_
총을 찾은 건가?
Calling to tell me
you found the gun?
그랬으면 좋겠는데
골목을 이 잡듯이 뒤져봤는데도
Wish I had good news.
We've combed the alley,
총을 찾지 못했어요.
can't find anything.
쓰레기통, 건물 안, 쓰레기봉지까지
다 뒤져본 것 맞는가?
Dumpsters, doors, garbage bags?
지붕 위로 총을 던져버렸을 지도 모르지
He could've tossed the gun
on a roof, maybe.
반장님, 총은 정말로 없어요.
Mac, there is no gun.
그 쪽은 어때요?
What's the situation there?
도주한 나머지 용의자의
도주 경로가 파악되었나요?
Do we have a lead on the
perp that got away?
아직 아냐,
그리고 이쪽 상황도 매우 좋지 못해.
Not yet, and things are
definitely not quieting down.
뉴스에 온통 우리 사건 얘기가 나오고 있고
온 동네 사람들이 나와서 시위 중이야
It's all over the news, and now
half the community is outside.
시위대 규모가 1,500명 쯤 돼보여
There's maybe
1,500 people out there.
시드 박사님이 뭔가를 찾아내셨으려나요?
Maybe Sid's got something.
그랬으면 좋겠네.
Well, he better.
홉킨스 경관이 거짓말을 하는지 아닌지를
확실히 알 수 있는 증거가 필요해
We need something to tell us
whether or not Hopkins is lying.
박사님?
Sid.
맥, 바깥쪽 상황은 어떤가?
Hey, Mac, is everything
all right over there?
아직은 버틸만 하지만
뭔가 만족스런 답변을 주지 못하면
Yeah, we're hanging in,
but it's gonna get ugly again
if we can't provide
any satisfactory answers.
바깥 시위대들이 또 난폭해질지도 몰라요
그렇다면 내가 찾아낸 게
바깥 언론에 흘러나가지 않길 간절히 바라자구
Well, let's hope what
I'm about to tell you
doesn't get leaked to the press.
_
시신에서 뭔가 찾았나요?
You're with the body?
부검은 아직 시작하지 않았네만
I haven't started the autopsy,
예비 검사를 좀 해봤는데
uh, but I performed some
preliminary examinations.
피해자의 체내에 알코올이나
마약 중독의 흔적은 보이지 않아
That tox showed no alcohol
or drugs in the victim's system.
더 중요한 사실은
피해자 티모시 브라운의 손에서는
But more importantly,
Timothy Brown's hands
총기 발사 잔여물이
전혀 검출되지 않았어
tested negative
for gunshot residue.
조는 현장에서 총기 발사와 관련한
증거를 좀 찾았다고 하던가?
Did Jo find any ballistic
evidence at the crime scene?
아뇨
No.
홉킨스 경관이 총 발사에 대해
거짓말을 하고 있는 거군요
Hopkins is lying about the gun.
진실을 해명해라!
We want the truth!
We want the truth! We want...
네, 피해자 시신에서
총기 발사잔여물이 발견되지 않았습니다
No, no GSR on the vic.
좀 잘못된 판단인 것 같은데요
I think that's the wrong call.
서장님, 홉킨스 경관을 구금하고
Respectfully, sir,
I think locking him up
대배심에 넘기는건
직무유기라고 판단됩니다.
and letting the grand jury
sort it out is a cop-out.
지금 이 건이 정치적으로
민감한 사안인 줄은 압니다만
I-I realize the political
implications of this,
좀 더 시간이 필요합니다.
but we deserve more time,
홉킨스 경관에 대해서도 대책없이
대배심에 넘겨버리기 전에
철저히 진실을 규명해야 합니다.
and Hopkins deserves better
than punting to the grand jury.
알겠습니다.
I understand.
분부대로 하겠습니다. 서장님
Whatever you say, Chief.
경찰서 내의 경관들과 형사들은
Officers and detectives
시위대가 경찰서를 더욱 압박해감에 따라
are more or less barricaded inside,
as demonstrators have virtually
surrounded the precinct.
내부를 탄탄히 무장 방어하고 있는데요
뉴욕 경찰에서는
Officials within the NYPD
are not releasing the names
아직도 故 티모시 브라운에게 총을 쏜
경찰관의 이름을 밝히지 않고 있는데요,
of the officers involved
in the shooting,
제보에 따르면 총격에 개입된 경관의 이름은
케빈 홉킨스 경관과 트레이 젠슨 경관이라고 합니다.
but we have learned that
they are officers Kevin Hopkins
and Trey Jensen.
_
아주 바깥에 현상수배
포스터를 붙일 작정이구만
Might as well hang
wanted posters outside.
케빈 홉킨스 경관은 뉴욕 경찰
근무 2년차의 경관으로
Officer Hopkins, a member of
the NYPD for the last two years,
국민신문고를 조회해본 결과
과거에도 문제가 있던 것으로 드러났는데요
has been brought before
the Civilian Complaint
Review Board in the past.
_
저 기자년이 정말!
Oh, come on, Victoria!
알고 있었던거야?
You know about that?
네, 홉킨스 경관은 예전에
가정폭력 신고에 응해 출동한 적이 있었죠
Yeah, he responded to a 911
call of a domestic disturbance.
자기 담배를 숨겼다고 해서
남편을 체포해달라는 여자의 신고였어요
A wife wanted her husband locked
up for hiding her cigarettes.
홉킨스 경관은 그 남편더러
이 참에 전화기도 숨겨버리라고 했고요
Hopkins asked the husband
to hide her phone, too.
그 불만접수는 그냥 묵살되었죠
The complaint was dismissed.
이 두 경관의
기록을 연결지어 볼 때..
ahold of both of the
officers' personnel files...
_
서장님은 뭐라고 하셔요?
What's the chief say?
서장님 뿐만 아니라
시장님이랑 지방검사까지 독촉하고 있어
It's not just Sinclair, it's
the mayor and the D.A., too.
너무 돌이킬 수 없게 되었으니
This thing spun out of control,
so they're saying,
"구금해버려
대배심보고 알아서 하라지"라는거야
"Just lock 'em up.
Let the grand jury sort it out""
정말 그랬으면 좋겠어요?
You satisfied with that?
전혀 아니지
Not at all.
어떻게 된 거예요?
You want to tell me
what's going on?
그 거짓말 그만두고
사실을 이야기할거라 약속하면 말해주지.
I'll tell you what's going on
when you stop lying to me.
무슨 말씀이시죠?
What's that supposed to mean?
티모시 브라운은 총을 소지하고 있지 않았어.
Timothy Brown didn't have a gun.
총도, 발사 잔여물도 없어.
No gun.
No ballistics.
똑같은 이야기를
골백번째 하고 있는 것 같네요
We've been over this
a hundred times.
I came around the corner...
그 자가 골목에 들어서서..
피해자의 손과 상의에서
총기 발사잔여물이 전혀 검출되지 않았어
He didn't have gunshot residue
on his hands or his jacket.
전혀, 쥐꼬리만큼도.
Nothing, not a speck.
그러니 대체 어떻게
돼먹은 일인가 해명해보겠는가?
You want to tell me
how that happens?
있잖아 자네,
나한테 거짓말할 필요 없네
See, the thing is,
you didn't have to lie.
그럴 필요가 없다고.
You didn't need it.
내가 맞춰볼까?
Here's what I think happened.
보석상을 턴 범인들을 추격했겠지
You chased a guy who just
robbed a jewelry store.
골목에 다다라 범인을 마주쳤는데
범인이 경찰의 지시에 불응했겠지
You came around the corner,
you identified yourself
as a police officer, he
disobeyed your command,
_
피해자가 반항하여 자네 총을
탈취하려 해서 자네가 가슴에 총을 쏜거지
he spun around with his hand
up by his chest, and you fired.
잘못된 일이 아니야
You did everything right.
진실된 증언이면 전혀 문제될 게 없어
The truth would've been enough;
the truth is enough.
하지만 남들 보기에 좋지 않을거라 생각해서
But you thought it
wouldn't look good,
그 자가 자네에게 총을 쐈다고 말한 거겠지
so you had to say he fired at you.
자네는 훌륭한 경찰관인데만
거짓말은 그만두고 사실을 이야기해보게
You're a good police officer, Kevin,
but you got to stop lying to me.
테일러 형사님
Detective Taylor, I respect you,
정말 진심으로 존경하지만
그 말씀은 용납할 수 없습니다.
I got respect for you,
but screw you.
그 놈이 제게 총을 겨누고
절 쏘려 했어요
That kid, he pointed a
gun and he shot at me,
이 사실은 제가 죽는 한이 있더라도
변함 없는 사실입니다.
and I will go to my grave
swearing by that.
절 현장에 보내주세요
Take me out there.
제가 직접 증명해보이겠어요
I will... I will
walk you through it.
보다시피 자네를 밖에 데려나가기는
너무 위험하다네
It's too dangerous
to bring you out there.
하지만 현장의 모습을
영상으로 보여줄 수는 있지
But we can bring the scene to you.
총기를 갖고 있는지 여부도 모를 사람을
이 골목에서 추격한다는건
저로서는 있을 수 없는 일이예요
There's no way
I'm chasing a guy
who may or may not have
a gun down this alley.
_
너는 현장에서 추격을 해 본 적도 없잖아
When's the last time
you chased anyone at all?
오른쪽으로 간 것 같아요
I think he went right.
터널 끝에서 우측으로 틀어보게 호크스
Hawkes, take a right at
the end of this tunnel.
알겠습니다 반장님
10-4, Mac.
오른쪽으로 간 것 맞나?
Are you sure he went right?
네, 확실히 오른쪽으로 갔어요
Yeah, he definitely went right.
피해자가 총을 쐈다는 곳이 여기인가?
Is this where he took the shot?
아뇨, 골목 오른편으로 나가자마자
바로 그런 건 아니었어요
No. No, it wasn't right
out of the dark alley.
좀 더 내려가주세요
Keep going down.
확실한가?
You sure?
네
Yeah.
네 거기..
Yeah, it was,
조금 좁은..
it was more narrow and...
여기는 198번
현재 골목 뒷쪽으로 추격 중이다
198 in pursuit down
the alley behind...
거기에 비상계단이 있었어요
There was, there was fire escapes.
좀 많이 좁은 비상계단이 있었어요
It was more narrow.
There was fire escapes.
잠깐만요
Hang on.
애덤 잠시 멈춰보게
Adam, stay there for a sec.
저게 맞는가?
Is this it?
그런 것 같아요
I think so.
모르겠네요
I'm not sure.
맞아요
Yeah.
저 코너예요
제가 저 자리에 있었던 게 기억나요
That is the corner.
I remember, I took cover.
저 벽에 기대서 범인의
이동 방향을 엿보려 했어요
I was leaning right against that wall.
_
지원 요청! 지원 요청!
10-13, 10-13!
범인이 총을 쐈다!
Shot's fired!
반장님! 여기에 총이 지나간
자리가 보여요
Mac, got an impact mark
on this pipe here.
_
애덤, 카메라 확대를 해 보게
Adam, can you zoom in?
_
호크스, 만일 티모시 브라운이
그 골목에 서서 총을 쐈다면
Hawkes, if Timothy Brown
was standing in that alley
그 자리에 탄피가 남아있을 거야
when he took the shot,
there's got to be a casing.
알겠습니다
All right.
신호를 주시면 멈출게요
Just tell me when to stop.
그 쯤이예요
Right about there.
그 자가 저 자리
바로 가운데에 서 있었어요
He was standing right
there in the center.
♪
_
제가 아직도 거짓말하는 것
같아보이나요?
You still think I'm lying?
_
진실을 해명하라!
We want justice!
아니 호크스, 그 탄피 갖고
바로 연구소로 돌아와서
No, Hawkes, go straight back
to the lab and get that casing
총탄 조회 프로그램이랑 맞춰보게
into Brass Catcher.
아마 그걸로 티모시 브라운이나
그 주변 무엇이든 연결시킬 수 있을거야
Maybe we can connect
this to Timothy Brown
or anyone else he runs with.
_
일이 골치아파지겠는데요
This is gonna get ugly again.
우리가 병력 지원을 아무리 많이 해도
And I don't care how many
reinforcements we call in,
저 자들은 금방 여길 뚫을 기세예요
if they want to get in,
they're getting in.
_
홉킨스랑 젠슨 경관을
여기에서 빼내야 하네
We got to get Hopkins
and Jensen out of here.
I'm with you on that,
but they're not going out
그 점은 동의하지만
시위대가 잔뜩 깔린 저 문으로는
못 나갈거예요
through those doors.
_
그러니 좋은 생각 있으면
귀띔 좀 해주세요
So, if you have any ideas,
I'm all ears.
앰뷸런스가 아직 여기 남아 있지?
Those ambulances are still
out back by the dock.
_
정의 없이는 평화도 없다!
no peace!
No justice, no peace!
정의 없이는 평화도 없다!
No justice,
no peace!
_
도와줘!
We need help!
여기 짭새들을 끌어내자!
Dispatch, get some cops out here!
_
저 새끼야!
끌어내!
Yo, that's one of them!
That's one of the guys!
_
도와주세요! 도와주세요!
Help me! Hey! Hey!
_
시민들은 길을 비키십시오!
경찰 대원들이 진입합니다!
Move out of the way!
Let the police through!
_
(시민1):저리 꺼져!
Get off me!
이리 와!
Come on!
- 괜찮은가?
- 네, 지금은요.
- You all right?
- I am now.
_
빨리 나가야 해요
어서 가요!
Let's get the hell out of here!
Let's go! Let's go!
_
♪
찾았군
Match.
제발, 뭔가 찾았다고 해줘
Lord, tell me you found something.
두 가지가 발견되었어요
I've got two somethings.
골목에서 발견한 탄피는 조회 결과
사건 두 건이랑 일치하는 걸로 나타났어요
Two matches in Brass Catcher
to the shell casings
recovered in the alley.
_
6주를 간격으로 두 건의
서로 다른 사건에서 총이 발사되었어요
Two different shootings,
six weeks apart.
6-4에서의 사건에서도 사용되었고,
애버뉴 Q x 12번가에서의 사건에서도
사용되었어요
Both in the 6-4,
both in the vicinity of Avenue Q
and 12th street.
_
제일 최근 건은 작년 12월에
일어난 사건이었어요
The most recent,
December of last year.
두 사건 모두 진범이 체포되진 않았어요
그런데 보석상 강도사건이랑 연계관계가
있는지는 의문이네요
Now, no arrests in either
case, but I'm not so sure
they're connected
to the jewelry store robbery.
_
맨하탄 122번가는 브룩클린
애버뉴 Q랑은 멀리 떨어진 곳인데?
122nd Street in
Manhattan is a long way
from Avenue Q in Brooklyn.
_
- 그렇죠
- 하지만 우리 생각처럼
먼 곳이 아닐 수도 있어
- Yeah. - But it may not
be as far as we think.
철조망을 넘느라 자켓을 버리고 간
그 범인의 자켓을 대니가 조사했잖아
That jacket that
belonged to the perp
who went over the
barbed wire fence
that Danny processed...
_
조사해보니 주머니에 구멍이 나 있었어
turns out, it had a hole
in the pocket.
그리고 자켓 안쪽에서
종이 조각을 발견했는데
He found a piece of paper
inside the lining
of the jacket.
_
물에 여러차례 씻겨진 종이였어
It had been washed a few times.
쓰여진 걸 복구해보니
수 개월 전에 발행된 소환장이었어
Turns out, it was a summons
issued a few months ago
64번가 경찰서에서
공공시설 내 음주를 이유로 발행한
소환장이었지
in the 64th Precinct
for drinking alcohol
in an open container
in public.
_
그 경찰서 주소가
애버뉴 Q의 4300번 블록이잖아
That was the 4300
block of Avenue Q.
좀전의 미해결 총격 사건 두 건이랑
가까운 위치네요
Right up the block from these
two unsolved shootings.
그러면 철조망을 넘어 도망간 범인이랑
미해결 총격 사건 두 건의
장소를 연결지을 수 있겠네요
So that connects
our guy who jumped
over the barbed wire fence
to the neighborhood
where the shootings occurred.
_
애버뉴 Q x 12번가는
근방의 동네지.
Avenue Q and 12th is a
residential neighborhood.
그 음주죄 소환장 덕에
범인의 활동 구역을 알아내게 됐어
So that drinking summons tells
me this is where they hang out,
거기에서 강도 사건
공범을 찾아보면 될 거야
and that's where we
need to be looking.
그런데 젠슨, 홉킨스 경관을 피신시켰으니
현장에 내보내 신원을 확인시킬 수도 없고
Yeah, but we don't have Jensen
or Hopkins to put into a car
to do an area search, and the
jewelry store owner can't I.D.
보석상 주인은 범인의 얼굴을
못 봤다고 했어요
보석상에는 감시카메라도 없었고
There were no cameras in the
jewelry store, and we don't have
경찰차 블랙박스에도
범인 얼굴이 찍히지 않았으니
a good screen shot from the
dash cam in the squad car.
범인이 어떻게 생겼는지 알 길이 없네
So we don't know who the
hell we're looking for.
_
홉킨스 경관은 어때요?
How's Hopkins?
시위대한테 두들겨맞았지만
He got roughed up pretty good.
지금은 괜찮아
이만하면 다행이지
But he's okay;
could've been worse.
시위대는 아직도 드센가요?
Any sign of the protest letting up?
시위대 규모가 더 확대되었어
None. Crowds have
actually gotten bigger.
경찰 국장님이 2급 보호를 명하셔서
Commissioner called
a Level 2 mobilization.
지원 병력이 더 늘어날 거야
More reinforcements are
on the way.
시위대를 잠재우기 위해서는
The only way this thing
is gonna die down
사건의 해답을 찾는 것밖에 없어
is if we get some more answers.
홉킨스랑 젠슨 경관이 쫓고 있었다던
제 2의 공범을 빨리 찾아내야 해
We need that other guy in the
alley with Hopkins and Jensen.
탄피에서 뭔가 건진 게 있나?
The shell casing...
did it get us anything?
보석상 강도범인 무리가
활동하던 구역의 동네를 찾아냈어요
It got us to a
neighborhood where one of
our jewelry store perps might hang.
_
그런데 그 공범의 얼굴을 확인해줄
증인이나 사진 자료가 필요해요
The problem is,
Mac, we need a photo
or a witness who can I.D.
홉킨스를 여기 데려오기 전에
젠슨을 데리고 잇기는 했는데
Jensen made it out of here
before they got Hopkins.
_
지금 본부에 불려갔어
He's at headquarters.
젠슨 경관은 철조망을 넘어
도망간 범인의 얼굴을 봤을 거야
He got a look at the guy
who went over the fence.
차에 태워서 그 현장으로 데려가 봐
Put him in a car
and get out there.
그런데 차 유리창 너머로
사람들 얼굴을 확인하게 하는 것만으로
범인을 어떻게 찾을 수 있겠어요?
Come on, finding them
hanging out in the streets
seems like a long shot.
_
맞는 말이지만 지금으로서는
이것 외에 방법이 없어
You might be right, but right now,
it's the only good lead we've got.
뉴스 첫 소식은 경찰이 비무장한
시민을 쏴죽인 사건에 대해
Tonight's top story
continues to be the community
unrest outside the 12th Street
Precinct in Manhattan
시민들이 맨하탄 12번가 경찰서 앞에서
시위를 벌이고 있는 현장의 소식입니다.
over the alleged shooting
of an unarmed man by police.
_
뉴욕 시장과 경찰 고위 위원은
The mayor and police
commissioner continue to call
시민들에게 진정해 줄 것을 요하고 있으나
시위대의 분노는 사그러들지 않고 있습니다.
for calm, but protesters
remain defiant.
일부 시민들은 故 티모시 브라운의 죽음을
경찰에 의한 잔혹한 살인이라 부르고 있습니다.
Some in the community
are labeling the death
of Timothy Brown
a cold-blooded murder.
_
저 기자 새끼들이
케빈 홉킨스랑 단 5분만 얘기해봐도
Any of those jackass
reporters that talk
to Kevin Hopkins for five minutes...
they'd realize
자기네들이 지금껏 싸지른게
얼마나 되도않은 개소리인줄 깨달을텐데요
how ridiculous that statement is.
_
경찰관 두 명 중 한 명이 연루된 것으로..
one of the
two police officers involved...
저 밖에 혹시 공범이 보여?
Recognize anybody?
케빈 홉킨스 경관은
26세 학생을 총으로 쏘아..
Officer Kevin Hopkins
shot the 26-year-old...
뭘 꼬라봐?
What you looking at?
아뇨
Nope.
저 패거리 중에 제가 쫓았던
그 놈은 안 보이네요
None of them are the guys
we were chasing down
잔혹하게 살인했다느니 하는 놈 말이죠
to murder in cold blood.
한편 미확인 용의자도 여전히 남아있는데요
The other unidentified
suspect remains at large.
네
Yeah.
그래요, 몸 조심하세요
All right, be safe.
_
아직 그 철조망을 넘어갔다는
공범은 못 찾았지만
No luck yet on the perp
who went over the fence,
계속 찾는 중이래요
but they're still looking.
반장님, 아무리 바쁘고 정신없으시겠지만
Boss, I don't want to tell you
how to conduct your business,
전화는 좀 받아주셔야죠
but you got to answer your phone.
반장님 음성사서함도 꽉 차있고요
Okay?
Your voicemail's all jacked up,
조 형사님도 전화를 안 받으시고
Jo doesn't pick up her phone...
I was literally
진짜 뭘 어떻게 하라는 지시를
받지 못했거든요
left unsupervised
for a really long time.
애덤, 무슨 일인가?
Adam, what's going on?
대체 저 시위대는 어떻게 뚫고 온 건가?
How the hell did you get
past that mob outside?
차를 한 20블록 밖에다가 주차시켜놓고
걸어왔죠
Well, I-I parked my car, like,
20 blocks away and I walked.
거짓말 안 하고 정말로
납치를 두 번이나 당할 뻔했고요
And I'm not gonna lie, I almost
got jacked a couple times,
하지만 보시다시피
but as long as I, you know,
저는 그 놈들한테 허공에 주먹을 날리고
pumped my fist up
in the air and yelled
소리도 치고 깡통도 차면서 물리쳐왔죠
some crazy things
and kicked over a garbage can,
저 진짜 짱이었어요
I was... I was good,
I was totally good.
알겠네, 그래서 하고 싶은 말이 뭔데?
Okay, what's so important?
티모시 브라운의 주머니에서 발견된
보석 있잖아요
The jewelry
that we found
in Timothy Brown's pocket...
_
저희는 지금껏 그걸 강도 사건
도난품으로 간주했잖아요.
okay, we all assumed
that it was
part of the robbery, right?
_
그 보석 대부분이
14캐럿 금으로 된 거더라고요.
Now, a lot of it was stamped
제가 귀금속 쪽에는 일가견이 있어서
14-karat gold, and I'm really
good with my precious metals,
그 중에 뭔가 이상하다는 걸 알아챘죠
so some of it
didn't look right,
그래서 그 굵은 팔찌를 검사해봤는데요
so I tested some of the
heavier-gage bracelets.
검사 결과 14캐럿 철이더군요
Turns out,
it was 14-karat iron.
inrochloric acid랑 가짜 금화를
녹여서 만든 거였어요
It dissolved
inrochloric acid
and had a phony gold stamp.
_
짝퉁이었어요.
Worthless.
그래서 제가 현장에 다시 나가서
Right?
So I went back out in the field
직접 발로 뛰어 확인해봤어요
and I... and I did
some more legwork,
정말 도움이 되었으면 좋겠네요
and I really hope that that's okay.
그래, 잘 했어
계속해봐
Yeah, it's fine.
Go on.
그 보석은 티모시 브라운의 것이었어요
The jewelry belonged to Brown, Mac.
티모시 브라운은 이걸 1블럭 떨어진
그 강도 사건 당한 보석가게에
저당잡히려 했던 거예요
All right? He was trying to
hock it at another jewelry store
about a block away from
the one that got robbed.
_
피해자는 약혼 반지를 사기 위해
이것저것 팔아 돈을 모으던 중이었어요
He was just trying to scrape
in a couple extra bucks
together to get this.
_
약혼 반지요
It's an engagement ring.
피해자는 여자친구에게
프로포즈를 하려 했던 거예요
He was gonna propose to his girl.
약혼반지의 다이아몬드에 새겨진
Now, I tracked down the store
일련번호를 조회해서 구입처를 추적해하여
through the serial number
of the diamond,
원래 소유했던 가게와 연락이 닿았죠
and I spoke to the owner.
사건 현장의 가게가 강도를 당할 동안
티모시 브라운은 거의 비슷한 시각에
다른 가게에서 약혼 반지를 사고 있던 거예요
Timothy Brows in there
around the same time
that the other store got hit.
_
반장님, 티모시 브라운은 강도 사건과
아무 상관도 없는 사람이었어요
Mac, Timothy Brown had nothing
to do with the robbery.
그 강도 사건의 진범 두 명은
여전히 바깥을 활보하고 있어요
Both those perps
are still out there.
모든 대원은 집중할 것
All units, be advised,
12번 팀이 오늘 아침에 있었던
보석상 강도 사건의
the 12th Squad is seeking
two males in connection with
범인으로 추정되는
용의자 두 명을 추적 중이다.
the jewelry store robbery
earlier today.
용의자는 두 명의 흑인 남성으로,
20~25세이며
They are two male blacks,
20 to 25 years old,
한 명은 검은 스키 자켓에
청바지 차림이고,
one wearing a black ski jacket
and blue jeans,
다른 한 명은 회색 후드티에
청바지 차림이다.
the other in a gray hoodie
and blue jeans.
이 용의자들은 브룩클린 애버뉴 Q의
4300 블럭에 자주 나타난다고 한다.
These males are known to
frequent the 4300 block
of Avenue Q in Brooklyn.
_
저 놈이예요
That's him.
철조망을 넘어 도망간 게
저 놈이예요
That's the guy
that went over the fence.
검은 스키 자켓!
Whoa, the guy in the
black ski jacket.
저 자식이 홉킨스가 쫓던 녀석이예요
He's the guy Hopkins was chasing.
- 젠슨, 여기서 기다려요
- 출동! 출동! 출동!
- Jensen, stay put.
- Go, go, go!
_
뉴욕 경찰이다!
Hey, NYPD!
이 쪽으로 나와 손을 머리 위로 들어라!
Come out right now with
your hands above your head!
뒤돌아서! 손 들어!
Turn around!
Show me your hands!
손 들으라고!
Hands up!
다들 괜찮아요?
Everybody okay?
저 녀석 빼고는 괜찮아
Yeah, everybody but him.
총이 없는데요?
There's no gun.
총 보셨어요?
Did you see a gun?
아니, 그, 그런데 우편함 안에
뭔가를 꺼내기 위해 손을 넣는 건 봤어
No, b-but I saw him reaching
for something in that mailbox.
_
이봐 레이, 순순히 협조하시지?
Come on, Ray, pull
yourself together.
우리도 알 건 다 알거든?
We're almost done.
나도 노력 중이라구요
Look, I'm trying, man.
내 불알친구가 죽었다고요!
That was my homeboy
you guys killed.
뭐 그래도 그 녀석이
초래한 일이지
Yeah, well, he made
a bad choice, Ray.
그 녀석이 총을 꺼내려 했어
He went for that gun.
키이스가 감방에서 나와서
After Keith came home from upstate,
날 보고 "다시는 내가 감방에 가나 보다"
라고 했는데
he said, "I'm never
going back to jail."
감방은 안 갔지만
가지 말아야 할 곳을 가버렸네요
I guess he wasn't lying.
그 총은 뉴욕 인근 여러 곳에서
사용되었어.
That gun has been around
the block a few times.
브룩클린에서 두 건,
Two shootings in Brooklyn.
그리고 오늘 보석상 강도 사건에서 한 건,
And then the jewelry
store robbery today.
그 총은 누구 소유지?
Who does it belong to?
딱히 누구 거랄 게 없어요
It belonged to everybody.
그 총은 그 자리에 늘 있는 물건이예요
That gun always in that mailbox.
마치..
It's like...
도서관에 가서
going to the library
or something.
책을 빌려서
Taking out a book.
필요할 때 쓰고
You go in there, you take it,
you need it, you use it,
사용한 뒤 갖다놓는
일종의 양심적 대여소같은 거예요
you put it back, that's it...
it's the honor system.
그래서 오늘 아침 너랑 키이스가
그 총을 꺼내다가
So earlier today, you and
Keith checked out a gun
보석상을 털으려고 썼다는 거네?
and then used it to hold
up a jewelry store?
아까도 말했잖아요
Look, I told you before, okay?
그걸 진짜 쏠 생각은 아니었다고요
We wasn't meaning to use it.
그 총은 그냥 사람들이
순순히 물건을 내주지 않을 때를
대비해서 가져간 거였다고요.
We was gonna front
on those people in case
they got bold or something.
_
그러면 너네들을 쫓아오는 경찰들한테
총을 쏘는 것도 계획 밖의 일이었냐?
And then maybe
shoot a few cops if they were
bold enough to chase you?
_
그 경찰아저씨를 죽이려 한 건 아니었다고요
Nah, I wasn't trying
to kill that cop.
그냥 그 아저씨를 향해 쏘려고 했을 뿐이죠
I was just trying to shoot him.
그냥 쏘려고 했을 뿐이다?
You were just trying
to shoot him?
...골목 뒷쪽으로...
in the alley behind, uh...
아니다! 되돌아가겠다!
Uh, negative! I'm doubling back!
_
지원 요청! 범인이 총을 쐈다!
10-13! Shots fired!
그 대여소 자리는
고장이 난 것처럼 보이게 늘 방치되어 있었죠
That place was
all tore up like it was
out of business or something.
_
총을 집어넣고
바로 지하철 입구로 내려가서
I hit the streets,
ditched into the subway,
지하철을 타고 브룩클린으로 튀었어요
그게 다예요
and hopped a train
back to Brooklyn, that's it.
권총강도 짓을 하긴 했지만
누구도 해하지 않았어요
We did that stickup,
but we didn't hurt nobody.
아냐 네가 해친 사람이 얼마나 많은데
You hurt so many people.
와줘서 고마워요
Thank you for coming.
팀이 죽은게 여전히 믿기지 않아요
Still can't believe Tim's dead.
말도 안 돼요
This is crazy.
바깥의 저 사람들도
팀에 대한 정의를 요구하기 위해
All those people out there
fighting the police,
경찰과 맞서 싸우고 있어요
demanding justice for Tim.
저들이 찾는 것은
우리가 찾는 것이기도 합니다.
They're looking for
what we've been
looking for: answers.
사건의 진실이죠.
뭐라도 찾으셨나요?
Do you have any?
그래서 아가씨를 여기 부른 거예요
That's why I asked you here.
진실을 알려드려야 해서요
I want you to hear the truth.
신문이나 뉴스로부터
잘못된 진실을 전해듣게 되기 전에 말이죠
Before you read some
version of it in the papers
or hear it on the news.
_
전 정말 진실을 알고 싶어요 형사님
I... I want to
understand, Detective.
정말이예요
Really, I do.
하지만..
But there is
형사님이 무슨 말을 하셔도 달라지지 않을
진실이 있죠
nothing you can say to me
that'll change anything.
그러니까..
I mean...
어떻게 경찰이라는 사람이
팀을 그렇게 잔혹하게 죽일 수 있죠?
How could that cop
just murder Tim like that?
_
잠시 같이 걸을까요?
Take a walk with me?
만일 제가 그 피해자 앞으로 뛰어들어
제 한 몸으로 총알을 막을 수 만 있다면
If I could step in front of
that bullet to save that man,
맹세컨대 정말 그렇게 할 거예요
I swear to God I would do it.
그랬다면 차라리 지금처럼
괴롭지는 않겠죠.
That would feel better than this.
전 무서웠어요 형사님
I was scared, Detective.
덜덜 떨고 있었죠.
I was shaking all over.
겁쟁이처럼..
Like a coward.
그 때 제가 만약
And maybe if I just...
침착했더라면
총을 막바로 쏘지는 않았을 거예요
kept my cool,
I would've hesitated.
그 사람이 총을 갖고 있지
않았다는걸 알았더라면..
I would've seen he had no gun.
제가 사람을 잘못 봤다는걸
알았더라면..
That he was the wrong guy.
만일 그 사람이 진범이었더라면?
And what if it was the right guy?
그리고 총을 갖고 있었더라면?
And he had a gun.
그러면 그 자리에서
네가 개죽음을 당했겠지
Then maybe it's you
lying in that alley.
그게 경찰의 세계라는 거야
That's the nature of
this job, Hopkins.
만약을 가정할 수는 없는거야.
There's no do-overs.
너는 주어진 상황 하에서
해야만 하는 최선의 방법을 택한 거야.
You're forced to make
the best decision
그 상황에서 1초라도 망설일 수는 없지
given the circumstances,
and you better make it fast.
그러라고 경찰 훈련을 받은 것이고
That's what
you're trained to do.
그게 네 임무이기도 해
That's what you did.
선배가 한 마디 해 주지
Let me tell you something.
진짜 겁쟁이같으면
사람을 죽일 각오의 무장 강도를
쫓아갈 용기조차 내지 못해
A coward doesn't run
after an armed man
who's trying to kill him.
_
겁쟁이라면 도망가버리지.
A coward runs away.
하지만 그 학생은 죽었잖아요
But that kid is dead now.
뭘 잘못한 것도 없는 학생이 말이죠
And he didn't do
a damn thing wrong.
그리고 그 학생의 가족이며..
And his family...
여자친구며..
and his girl...
제가 그들 앞에서
어떻게 고개를 들 수가 있죠?
what do I say to them?
죄책감을 느끼는 건 당연해.
You can feel bad about that.
죄책감을 단 1초라도 느끼지 않는다면
오히려 그게 더 이상한 거지
If you didn't, I'd think
you didn't have conscience.
_
그 꼬마는..
That kid's dead
어떤 두 개자식들이 보석상을
털기로 해서 죽게 된 거야
because two sons of bitches
decided to rob a jewelry store.
이뿐이지.
Simple as that.
바로 그 순간 용의자는
At the very same moment
our suspect was
현장의 뒷문으로 도망쳐나갔고,
disappearing through the
back door of the theater...
팀은
Tim
보석상 강도범의 반대 방향에서
appeared in the alley
그 골목으로 들어가고 있었죠
coming from
the opposite direction.
단순히 해명하려는 것이 아니라
I'm not asking you
사건의 전모를 정확히 아셨으면
하는 바람에서 말씀드리는 거예요
to excuse what happened,
I just want you
to understand why.
_
그래요.
I get it.
용의자와 팀의 옷이
우연히도 똑같았죠
They were wearing
the same clothes,
피부색도 같았고요.
they had the same color skin.
그.. 경찰은 팀을 보고
자신에게 총을 쏜 범인으로 착각한 거였죠
That... cop thought that Tim
was the one shooting at him.
잘못된 일이었어요
It was wrong.
경찰관이 실수를 했고..
He made a mistake, he...
사람을 잘못 쐈죠
killed the wrong man.
그랬죠.
Yes, he did.
아무 죄도 없는 착한 사람을요
An innocent man, a good man.
그리고 그 경관이 저지른 실수는
남은 생애 동안 짊어질 죄값으로 남을 거예요
And he'll have to live with
the burden of that mistake
for the rest of his life.
_
이런 식으로 소식을 전해드리게 되어
대단히 죄송하지만..
I'm sorry there was
no easy way to do this, but...
아셔야 할 게 또 있어요
I thought you should know.
팀은 이걸 주머니에 갖고 있었어요
Tim had this in his pocket.
아가씨에게 드리려던 거였죠.
He was planning
to give it to you.
"오늘 하루를 평생의 삶처럼."
("Today is life.")
"Today is life."
"당신 생애 최고의 날은"
("The only life you're sure of.)
"The only life you're sure of.
"바로 오늘 하루로 만들어지는 것이다"
(Make the most of today.")
Make the most of today."
팀이 대학 때문에 떨어져 있을 동안
주고받았던 편지에 늘 끝맺음말로 쓴 말이었죠.
That's how Tim signed off
all his letters to me
when he was away at college.
_
어찌보면 예언이 되었네요.
Seems kind of prophetic now.
고인의 명복을 빕니다.
I'm sorry.
아가씨,
Miss Bell.
아, 됐어요
Uh, no.
안 가질래요.
Please.
저걸 보면 이제는 가질 수 없게 된
팀과의 미래가 생각날 뿐이예요
Only remind me of
what could have been.
시위대의 규모는 여전합니다만
The numbers
have not diminished,
시위의 정도는 뉴욕 시장이
but the intensity of the protest
seems to have waned
for the moment,
시위대 대표를 직접 만나서
티모시 브라운의 죽음에 대한
해명을 하기로 약속한 뒤로
after word that the mayor
has agreed to meet
with community leaders
and answer questions regarding
the death of Timothy Brown.
많이 약화되었습니다
_
故 브라운의 오랜 애인 토리 벨 씨는
Brown's longtime
girlfriend, Tori Bell,
경찰의 요청에 의해 방금 전
경찰과 만남을 가졌는데요
was summoned to the precinct
a short time ago by police,
추측해보건대..
leading to speculation...
저기 나왔어!
There she is!
잠시만요
H-Hold on.
벨 양이 경찰서를 빠져나오고 있습니다.
It appears Miss Bell is
emerging from the precinct.
토리 씨, 홉킨스 경관을 원망하시나요?
Tori, do you blame Hopkins?
토리 씨, 경찰 쪽에서 뭐라고 해명하던가요?
Tori, are they making excuses...
_
홉킨스 경관의 징역살이를 원하시나요?
Do you want Officer
Hopkins to go to jail?
벨 양, 경찰이 뭐라고 하던가요?
Miss Bell, what are police saying?
말씀해주시죠!
What
can you tell us?
_
음..
Uh...
제가 말할 수 있는 건
I can tell you that
오늘은 제 생애 최악의 날이라는 겁니다.
today is the worst day of my life.
티모시의 유가족들과 티모시를 사랑했던
사람들에게도 최악의 날이기도 합니다.
It's the worst day in the
lives of Timothy's family
and the people who loved him.
_
하지만 오늘은 홉킨스 경관에게도
생애 최악의 날이기도 합니다.
But it's also the worst day
in the life of Officer Hopkins.
잠깐만요
Hold on.
제발
Please.
이 모든 것 그만둬주세요.
All of this has to stop.
_
홉킨스 경관은 살인자가 아닙니다.
That officer didn't
wake up this morning,
오늘 아침에 일어나 출근을 하고
사건에 출동했던 건 살인을 하기 위함이 아닙니다.
go to work and set out to kill Tim.
팀의 죽음은 그저
두 범죄자가 오늘 아침에 일어나
That happened because two
men woke up this morning
동네의 가게를 습격해
and decided that they were gonna
come to this neighborhood
남의 것을
훔치려다가 일어난 불행입니다.
and steal what doesn't
belong to them.
그 두 범죄자들은 경찰관을
쏴죽이려 했습니다.
They tried to take
that policeman's life
우리 도시의 치안을 위해
노력하는 경찰관을 말입니다.
while he was protecting ours.
그리고 저는 언젠가...
And I hope...
언젠가는 홉킨스 경관을 용서할 수 있겠죠.
someday that maybe I can find a way
to forgive Officer Hopkins.
_
하지만 저는 총을 들고
그 강도 사건을 벌인
But I will never forgive
those two men
그 두 범죄자는 절대 용서하지 않을 겁니다.
that came here with a gun.
그 범죄자들의 행동으로 인해
Because their actions
그 보석 가게의 모든 보석보다
수백 배 더 소중한 제 평생의 사랑이
took something from me a
hundred times more valuable
무고하게 희생되었으니까요.
than all of the jewelry
in that store.
그 범죄자들은
제 평생의 사랑을 앗아갔습니다.
They stole the love of my life.
♪
이 크고 복잡한 도시의 경찰관으로서
As police officers
in this big, complicated city,
우리는 수많은 비극을 마주하게 된다.
we see so much bad.
증오와 폭력으로 가득찬 수많은 영혼들
So many souls filled
with hatred and violence.
그들을 찾아내고,
And it's our job
to look for them,
추격하여 눈 앞에 앉혀놓는 것이
우리 경찰의 일일 것이다.
chase after them
and confront them.
_
시간이 지나면, 그들도
우리와 함께하는 착한 사람이 될 수 있다.
Over time, they can
become all we see.
사람에겐 악(惡)도 있지만,
As with all evil,
내면에는 언제나 선(善)함이 있기 마련이다
some good will
always come from it.
그 선함으로 인해 우리는
가장 일에 열정적이고,
It can bring us together with
some of the most dedicated,
존경스럽고, 한없이 착한,
평생을 함께 하고픈 사람들과
honorable,
kind-hearted people
더불어 함께 살 수 있는 것이다.
we could ever hope to meet.
그 선함은 우리 마음에
평생을 함께 할 수 있는 사랑을 가득 채워주고
It can fill hearts
with a love so strong
that it will endure forever...
_
일생의 가장 큰 고비까지 함께 견뎌 줄
평생의 좋은 친구를 만들어준다
...and create
unbreakable friendships
that will last
even in the face of life's
most difficult challenges.
_
건배해요 여러분!
Cheers, everybody.
건배!
Cheers.
때때로 선인(善人)은
우리가 가장 필요로 할 때,
Sometimes, the good
comes when we most need it
그리고 가장 기대치 못한 순간에 찾아온다.
and least expect it.
그런 사람을 알아챌 정도로
운이 좋다면,
If we are lucky enough
to notice it,
하늘에 우러러
감사히 여겨야 한다,
set our eyes upon it
and appreciate it,
세상 모든 나쁜 것들을
잊게 만들 수 있을 정도로 소중한 것이기 때문이다.
it can almost make us forget
all of the bad.
"오늘 하루를 평생의 삶처럼."
("Today is life.")
"Today is life.
"당신 생애 최고의 날은"
("The only life you're sure of.)
"The only life you're sure of.
"바로 오늘 만들어지는 것이다"
(Make the most of today.")
Make the most of today."
지혜의 글귀이면서,
Words of wisdom.
잘못 발사된 총알에 의해 짧은 삶을 마감한
한 무고한 영혼이 남긴 선함의 흔적이기도 하다
A slice of goodness
passed on by an innocent soul
whose life was cut short
by an errant bullet.
_
그 글귀는 내 앞으로 남은 인생을
바꿔버릴 결정에 앞서 간직할
These are words that will
always stay with me,
그리고 앞으로 평생 간직할,
격언이 될 것이다
words that are about to change
the course of my life forever.
_
내가 바라던 건 이런 게 아니었는데 말야
This is not how I
imagined it would happen.
네가 어떻게 상상해왔는지도
사실 잘 모르겠고..
I-I don't know if
it's how you imagined
it would happen, or...
_
사실 이런게 일어날 거라고
생각이나 했을지는 모르겠지만
if you even imagined it
happening at all, but...
무슨 소리를 하는 거야?
I'm not sure what you're saying.
빨리 들어가서 와인이나 한 잔 하자
L-Let's go in and
have a glass of wine.
- 내가 불 때울게...
- 아냐
- I'll make a fire...
- No.
아냐 아냐, 여기 있어봐
No, no, no, stay here.
1분 1초라도 기다릴 수가 없어
I don't want to wait
another minute.
사실 난 반지도 없고
I don't have a ring.
대단한 멘트를 준비한 것도 아니고
Or a speech.
싸구려 샴페인이라도 가져왔어야 했는데
그러지도 못했어
I-I wasn't even able to
stop and pick up a cheap
bottle of champagne.
_
이렇게 내 심장을 두근거리게 할 사람을
만나게 될 줄은 몰랐어
I never thought I'd
feel like this again.
당신은 내 인생 최고의 존재야
You're everything
that's good in my life.
우리 수많은
역경을 함께 헤쳐왔잖아
_
We've been through
so much together.
당신이 필요해
당신을 원해.. 그리고..
I need you, Christine,
I want you and I...
당신 없는 삶이란 상상할 수조차 없어
I can't imagine my
life without you.
난..
I don't want to...
_
내 남은 생애를 당신과 함께 하고 싶어
I just want to spend the rest
of my life with you by my side.
오..
Oh.
크리스틴...
Christine...
나와 결혼해주겠어?
will you marry me?
그럼!
Yes.
물론이고말고
Of course I will.
오,,
Oh.
내가 바라던 프로포즈대로야
This is exactly how I imagined it.
그동안 CSI 뉴욕 시즌 1~9을 사랑해주신
시청자 여러분께 감사드립니다.
sync and corrections by bellows
www.addic7ed.com
한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
English subtitles by
bellows from addic7ed.com